ABDIAS BALDIVIEZO

Salt Lake City, UT - abadias618@gmail.com - 801 875 0504 abadias618.github.io - linkedin.com/in/albertobaldiviezo

Results-driven SWE specialized in AI with a combined experience of 4 years. Possesses the ability to quickly <u>Adapt</u> to any team, person, technology, or project in order to make great things happen!

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - 06/2024 | Graduate Teaching Assistant | School of Computing - University of Utah

- Taught Python weekly in lab classes of 30 students and in lectures of approx. 150 students.
- Applied Python to projects using: Distributed Computing, HPC services, NoSQL (Column and document oriented), XAI, NLP-NLU-NLG, DL:GANs-RNNs-CNNs, RLHF, Data Mining, MLOps.

01/2021 - 09/2022 | **Software Engineer** | InfoRight - Information Technology and Services

- Full SDLC for Mining equipment management with React, Node, AzureSQL, AWS(EC2, S3), REST.
- Implemented integrations for MS PowerApps (Geolocation, Azure Datalake, Code Compilation).
- Performed Data QA in start-up environment with Great Expec. and Airflow for Pipelines.
- Scaled Web Scraping Product (Selenium, Beautiful-Soup, Node) to support thousands of records.

01/2020 - 04/2021 | Software Developer | BYU-Idaho - Business Solutions

- Developed Java & JS interface for TeamDynamix Integrations processing more than 500K records.
- Developed time series prediction models (Prophet, ARIMA) to optimize scheduling and management for university HR, saving 10 man-hrs a week.
- Proposed and coded Chatbot (Flask, NLTK, Knowledge Bases, Info. Extraction) first initiative.

SKILLS

Cloud: AWS, Azure, Databricks, Heroku.
Code: C++, Go, Java, Javascript, Python, R.
Data: GreatExpec., dplyr, Numpy, Pandas.
DBs: Azure SQL DB, MySQL, MongoDB,
MSSQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL.

Deep Learning: NN-Archs, PyTorch, Tensorflow. Dev/MLOps: Airflow, Bash, Conda, Docker, Git, Linux, MLflow, PyTest, AWS Sagemaker. Generative AI: LLMs, Stable Diffusion,

Transformer Models.

LLMs: HuggingFace, LangChain, RAG.
NLP: Info. Extraction, NLTK, Parsing, SpaCy.
Parallel & Accel: CUDA, Spark, TensorRT.
Reinforcement Learning: RLHF, Q-Learning.
Statistics: Bayesian Methods, Modeling,
Numpy, Regression, Scikit-Learn, SciPy.
Unsupervised ML: Clustering, K-means, PCA.
Viz: ggplot2, Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn.
Web: BeautifulSoup, Bootstrap, Flask, Node,
PlayWright, React, Selenium, Shiny, Spring.

RECENT PROJECTS

- (1) One/few/zero-shot prompt study of multimodal IDEFICS vs SoTA models in image classification.
- (2) Study of Hyena Hierarchy Filters to reduce quadratic operations (attention) in Transformer models.
- (3) Artificial Creativity (Strong vs Weak Al, Creativity Intersection Human/Machine) Phil of Mind.
- (4) Multilingual Named Entity Recognition BIO-tagger trained with PAN-X data (4 languages).

EDUCATION

08/2022 - 06/2024 | **MS Computing - Artificial Intelligence** | University of Utah 01/2020 - 04/2021 | **BS Software Engineering** | Brigham Young University Idaho 01/2018 - 12/2019 | **AS Software Development** | Ensign College

NATURAL LANGUAGES: English (Proficient), Portuguese (Proficient), Spanish (Native)